<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ReflexologyBromley | Reflexology | Indian Head Message | Hypnotherapy</title>
    <description>Reflexology, Indian Head Message and Hypnotherapy in Bromley areas</description>
    <link>https://reflexologybromley.co.uk//</link>
    <atom:link href="https://reflexologybromley.co.uk//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Fri, 09 Mar 2018 13:30:56 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Mar 2018 13:30:56 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.4.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Reflexology and PMS</title>
        <description>&lt;h2&gt;Reflexology for Premenstrual Syndrome (PMS)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you suffer from migraines, headaches, irritability, depression like conditions around your monthly cycle? You are not alone as many women suffer from these conditions every month in silence. It might be time for you to try out reflexology. Reflexology can help with PMS, migraines, anxiety, hormonal issues and other health issues. So what is reflexology?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://reflexologybromley.co.uk//img/free-from-migrane.jpg&quot; title=&quot;reflexology for PMS&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is a gentle, non-invasive technique which can help you relax, de-stress and bring into balance your state of mind. If done correctly by a qualified and experienced therapist it can help in prevention and recovery from various psychosomatic conditions. Reflexology works wonders. I have seen some profound emotional and physical changes in my clients after the reflexology sessions. From children to the elderly, people from all walks of life, everyone finds themselves energised and renewed after a session of this amazing technique.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the therapy session, a reflexologist looks at the issue in a holistic manner looking into the root cause of the issue faced by the client. In the case of pre-menstrual syndrome (PMS) it is no different as the therapist works on the endocrine system together with other areas such as the nervous system, liver and the glands in the body. Around the menstrual cycle a woman can experience over 100 different types of conditions although there is still a lack of clarity as to why it happens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These conditions can range from &amp;ndash; 
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;i class=&quot;fa fa-check&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;migraines and headaches&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;i class=&quot;fa fa-check&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;anxiety&lt;/li&gt; 
&lt;li&gt;&lt;i class=&quot;fa fa-check&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;irritability&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;i class=&quot;fa fa-check&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;constipation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;i class=&quot;fa fa-check&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;weight gain&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;i class=&quot;fa fa-check&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;depression&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;i class=&quot;fa fa-check&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;crying spells&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;i class=&quot;fa fa-check&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;tiredness&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the fact remains that this conditions effects women all around the world. Some studies have found that the hormonal changes that take place during the menstrual cycle contribute greatly to this debilitating condition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The results of controlled studies such as the one done by Oleson T. &amp;amp; Flocco W. (Randomized Controlled Study of Premenstrual Symptoms &amp;ndash; http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/8233263) have demonstrated a significantly greater decrease in premenstrual symptoms for the women given true reflexology treatment than for the women in the placebo group. In this study 35 women with PMS condition participated and received reflexology sessions with positive results. Post-menstrual syndrome can upset normal life leading to issues in personal relationships as well. Reflexology can bring a balance into your life. It is possible that migraines, headaches, mood swings and other conditions can be a thing of the past.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is stopping you? Try a session of reflexology today.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2016 08:43:59 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://reflexologybromley.co.uk//therapies/2016/01/07/massage-relax/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://reflexologybromley.co.uk//therapies/2016/01/07/massage-relax/</guid>
        
        
        <category>therapies</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Reflexology and MS</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Reflexology treatment has shown positive results in people suffering from Multiple Sclerosis. In various case studies, the participants experienced reduction in pain and improvement in daily functions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;i class=&quot;fa fa-quote-left&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;In an article on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mstrust.org.uk/a-z/reflexology&quot;&gt;Multiple Sclerosis Trust&lt;/a&gt; website, 71 people with MS were randomly seleted in a blind study to ascertain the effect of reflexology of which 53 patients completed the study.  These people showed significant improvements in the mean scores of paraesthesia (abnormal sensations such as pins and needles), bladder symptoms, muscle strength and spasticity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also access full study on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.researchgate.net/publication/10606828_Reflexology_treatment_relieves_symptoms_of_multiple_sclerosis_A_randomized_controlled_study&quot;&gt;Research Gate&lt;/a&gt; website by clicking here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clients I have worked with, who have had to live with MS, have benefited from increased energy levels, reduction in pain, improvement in daily functions such as bladder control and overall sense of wellbeing after reflexology sessions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, many auto-immune conditions such as Crohn’s and Multiple Sclerosis react positively to reflexology. Complementary therapies such as reflexology don’t have side effects, which in itself is a great plus. Overall, more studies such as above are needed so that alternative practices are used as opposed to medications which can have adverse reactions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reflexology is not foot massage and should be taken as a serious therapy. Please engage an experienced therapist.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2016 11:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://reflexologybromley.co.uk//reflexology/2016/01/03/multiple-sclerosis/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://reflexologybromley.co.uk//reflexology/2016/01/03/multiple-sclerosis/</guid>
        
        
        <category>reflexology</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Seasonal depression</title>
        <description>&lt;h2&gt;Seasonal Affective Disorder (SAD) a myth?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to a study published on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nhs.uk/news/2016/01January/Pages/Seasonal-affective-disorder-may-be-a-myth-study-argues.aspx&quot; title=&quot;Seasonal Affective Disorder&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;NHS website,&lt;/a&gt; &amp;nbsp;Seasonal Affective Disorder or SAD is a myth. Do you agree? Have you suffered from seasonal disorder leading to depression?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The website gives the following symptoms as a result of SAD -&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;i class=&quot;fa fa-check&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;a persistent low mood&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;i class=&quot;fa fa-check&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;a loss of pleasure or interest in normal everyday activities&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;i class=&quot;fa fa-check&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;irritability&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;i class=&quot;fa fa-check&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;feelings of despair, guilt and worthlessness&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;i class=&quot;fa fa-check&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;feeling lethargic (lacking in energy) and sleepy during the day&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;i class=&quot;fa fa-check&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;sleeping for longer than normal and finding it hard to get up in the morning&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;i class=&quot;fa fa-check&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;craving&amp;nbsp;carbohydrates&amp;nbsp;and gaining weight&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thankfully, NHS website does not fully agree with the study and advices those who suffer depression to take various proactive actions such as contacting the GP, doing exercise, eating healthy etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whatever the case may be, depression can remain dormant without anyone noticing it. Complementary therapies such as reflexology, head massage and hypnotherapy can assist with releasing stress and anxiety built up during winter months. Reflexology and Indian Head Massage have uplifting and positive effect on people in general.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2016 11:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://reflexologybromley.co.uk//reflexology/2016/01/02/seasonal-affective-disorder/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://reflexologybromley.co.uk//reflexology/2016/01/02/seasonal-affective-disorder/</guid>
        
        
        <category>reflexology</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Relaxation Time</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Try an Indian head massage taster session for only £10. You can book now by calling 07521 378 701 or 020 8407 6398.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the taster session you will get an insight into this wonderful relaxing technique which is a stress buster amongst other things. It promotes relaxations, reduces stiffness in back and neck areas, increases concentration levels and thus boosts productivity and much more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It originated in India where it is called Champee or Champissage, an intense massage on the upper back, neck, arms, head and the face areas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This complementary therapy is a great way to feel re-energised at any time of the day. Not many people would say no to this wonderful technique once they experience it! Read more about it here or book now.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 18 Apr 2015 09:43:59 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>https://reflexologybromley.co.uk//therapies/2015/04/18/reflexology-pms/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://reflexologybromley.co.uk//therapies/2015/04/18/reflexology-pms/</guid>
        
        
        <category>therapies</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
